Music is a music, drama film directed by Sia.
Zu, a free spirit estranged from her family, suddenly finds herself the sole guardian of her half-sister, Music, a
teenager on the autism spectrum whose whole world order has been beautifully crafted by her late grandmother.
The film soon challenges whether it is Zu or Music who has a better view of the world, and
that love, trust, and being able to be there for each other is everything.
Zu, played by Kate Hudson.
Ebo, played by Leslie Odom Jr..
Music, played by Maddie Ziegler.
Millie, played by Mary Kay Place.
Felix, played by Beto Calvillo.
Evelyn, played by Juliette Lewis.
Music is a 2021 American musical drama film directed by singer-songwriter Sia.
The film was co-written by Sia and Dallas Clayton,
and stars Kate Hudson, Leslie Odom Jr.
and Maddie Ziegler.
It marks Sia's feature film directorial debut.
The film follows Zu, a newly sober drug dealer who becomes the sole guardian
of her half-sister Music, a teenage non-verbal autistic girl.
The film began development following Sia's announcement of the project in 2015.
Originally intended as a non-musical film, it was subsequently re-conceived as
a musical with a larger budget, and was filmed in mid-2017.
A studio album by Sia was also released in connection with the
film, including some of the 10 songs she wrote for it.
Music was released in Australia on January 14, 2021, by StudioCanal, and in select IMAX theatres in the United States for one
night on February 10, 2021, followed by an on-demand release on February 12, 2021, by Vertical Entertainment.
The film was a box office failure, grossing
$645,949 against its $16 million budget.
Music received generally negative reviews from critics, with most
criticism stemming from its depiction of autism.
It was nominated for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy and Best Actress – Motion Picture Comedy or Musical (Hudson) at the 78th Golden Globe Awards, but was
also nominated for four Golden Raspberry Awards, winning Worst Actress for Hudson, Worst Supporting Actress for Ziegler and Worst Director for Sia.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, autism,
macabre, celebratory, disrespectful.
The tone is emotional.